

London (Ontario), Canada

Github: github.com/olestourko otourko@mailbox.org Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/olestourko 647-703-7906 Blog: olestourko.github.io

SUMMARY

An experienced and adaptable software developer who likes trying new things. Backend development is where I tend to have the most fun.

GENERAL: OOP, Design Patterns, Automated Testing, Linux, Git

LANGUAGES: Python, PHP, Java, Javascript, C#, C

BACKEND: MVC, SQLAlchemy, SQL, Flask, Laravel, MongoDB, Apache/Nginx

FRONTEND: ¡Query, Knockout.js, HTML, SASS/CSS

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer — BriteCore, United States (100% Remote)

August 2018 — Present

A comprehensive SaaS platform for insurance companies.

- Implement new user stories and fix defects within a large, mature codebase.
- Work in a 100% distributed team, with all of its unique advantages, risks, and challenges.
- Take de facto ownership of certain features that I tend to work on often.
- Improve development tools by fixing nuisances and performance issues.

Tech: Python, MySQL, Pandas, Linux, Git, Rally

Full Stack Web Developer — Digital Extremes Ltd, London Ontario A large Canadian game studio best known for the title *Warframe*.

November 2015 - July 2018

- Key contributor to and maintainer of warframe.com (~0.5M unique daily visitors).
- Automate common tasks and write scripts to sync large datasets.
- Integrate internal and third-party APIs with our web services.
- Work closely with other web developers, departments, and remote team members.

Tech: Laravel, PHP, Python, MySQL, MongoDB, Javascript, SASS, Linux, Perforce, JIRA

Full Stack Web Developer — Northern Commerce Inc, London Ontario A digital agency specializing in ecommerce projects.

April 2014 — October 2015

- Full stack Magento development: implementing custom functionality and integrating extensions.
- Participate in code reviews.

Tech: Magento, PHP, MySQL, Javascript, CSS, Linux

PERSONAL PROJECTS

OpenPay London

February 2018 — Present

An open-source salary information tool for London, Ontario. Reliable information is limited in my city and I want to fix that.

Website: londontechpay.ca Source Code: github.com/olestourko/open-tech-pay

- Set project goals and successfully launched a working core version.
- Built a completely decoupled frontend and RESTful backend.
- Continuously improving the project based on feedback from the local developer community.

Tech: Python, Flask, Docker, Knockout.js

Electric Bike

August 2020 — Present

I built a long-range electric bike during lockdown. This isn't a software project but it does involve some C programming. It was very fun and required much research, learning, and planning. I'm still building on it.

Link: https://imgur.com/a/HulJv0D

- Built a 1.28kwh battery bank which gives a range of ~100km.
- Learned basic welding, which I used to build a cargo trailer and make frame modifications.
- (In progress) writing a Linux-compatible motor configuration tool in C because the vendor-supplied software is Windows only: https://github.com/olestourko/bbsx-serial

Tech: C, DC electronics, flux core welding, soldering, woodworking

SDBudget

February 2017 - August 2017

A personal budgeting and cashflow forecasting application. Based on my personal spreadsheet system at the time, which works on the concept of a rolling surplus or deficit.

Website: <u>olestourko.github.io/sd-budget</u> Source Code: <u>github.com/olestourko/sd-budget</u>

- Successfully planned and completed the project.
- Used appropriate software design patterns to completely decouple the backend and frontend.
- Wrote an extensive unit testing suite and created concise user documentation.

Tech: Java (SE8), JavaFX, jOOQ, H2DB, JUnit

EDUCATION

BSc. Computer Science - Ryerson University

2014

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Deep Learning Specialization - Deeplearning.ai / Coursera Machine Learning — Stanford University via Coursera Parallel Programming in Java — Rice University via Coursera LPIC-1 Linux System Administrator / Comptia Linux+ M101P: MongoDB for Developers

Completed April 2018 Completed August 2017 Completed October 2017 Completed February 2017 Completed December 2015